Artur Schaefer

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

artur.schaefer2@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/artur-schaefer

Summary

I've been working with Android for over four years, focusing on Kotlin and Java as the main programming languages. Also, I'm a Flutter enthusiast and enjoy the framework and how easy it is to build applications. Work in a broad range of projects, including mobility, social media, real estate, fintech, and e-commerce.

I finished a Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems in June 2018 and, since there, I've been working mainly with Android. While doing the Bachelor's Degree, I was doing an Android Developer Nanodegree from Udacity, which I finished in October 2018. In this course, they introduced me to the best practices of Android and the new Jetpack Architecture Components.

I like to share knowledge in every opportunity that I have. I'd started to make talks, write articles, and mentor some people, and I hope to help the community more and more.

Experience



Software Engineer

Glovo

Mar 2022 - Present (4 months +)

Android Developer

SQLI

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022 (7 months)

I worked on the Nespresso e-commerce project at the Android part. We're refactoring e restructuring a huge codebase from Java to Kotlin. My role in this process is to support old features fixing bugs and, propose improvements to the project. The main goal is to use the newer Jetpack libraries to make the app more fluid and maintainable.

P

Android Developer

PicPay

Oct 2020 - Aug 2021 (11 months)

- Mobile developer using Kotlin and Java for Android Applications
- Focus on security and access app
- Tracking of users' behaviors in our features
- Kanban as Agile Methodology
- Built code with SOLID, Clean Architecture, and MVVM
- Use tools like RxJava, Koin, Espresso, JUnit, Android Jetpack, Biometrics, Firebase ML Kit, and others



Hotmart

Aug 2019 - Oct 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- · Android development, using Kotlin / Java, in a multidisciplinary team
- The app, Sparkle, had more than 1 million downloads on the Google Play Store
- In the application I handled with creation and consumption of media (Videos, Audios, Photos, PDF, and texts).
- The two biggest challenges faced were: redoing the flow of content consumption and increasing the health of the application, reducing crashes, and improving user usability.
- Main architecture design used: MVVM + Clean Architecture
- The most used tools/libraries: ExoPlayer, FFMpeg, DownloadManager, WorkManager, Room, CameraX (and other camera APIs)

Android Developer

Usemobile

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year)

- Part of the Android application development team, using Kotlin and Java in all projects.
- Use of current architecture patterns, such as MVP, MVVM, and VIPER.
- Use of agile methodologies SCRUM, XP (Extreme Programming) during the development process.
- Handling of information from servers through APIs.
- Experience in using Google APIs including Firebase (Realtime database, notifications, Crashlytics, Login, Events), Google Places, and Google Vision.

Information Technology Support Assistant

Synergia Consultoria Socioambiental

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 8 months)

- Performed technology support activities, involving systems and network infrastructure, data analysis, as well as filtering for consistency of information collected through field activities.
- Development of applications to support various activities, using technologies such as VBA, Java, PHP, MySQL, and PostgreSQL.



Volunteer Researcher

CNPq

Jul 2016 - Jun 2017 (1 year)

- Developing a work plan for the application and assessment of modeling services using archimate in actual cloud-services scenarios.
- Results were presented at the 1st IFES Integration Day, in October 2017 at Campus Colatina.
- The research was carried out while a student at the Instituto Federal Espírito Santo Campus Colatina.

Programming class monitor

Ifes - Instituto Federal do Espírito Santo

Jul 2016 - Dec 2016 (6 months)

 Supported students in technology courses programming topics at IFES Campus Colatina. Helping Bachelor of Information Systems, and Integrated Computer Technician students. • The languages I worked with during this period were mainly Python, C / C ++, and Java. HTML, Javascript, and PHP were occasionally requested and were also worked on during the period.



Undergraduate Research Assistant

CNPq

Jan 2015 - Jan 2016 (1 year 1 month)

- · Work period related to the technological initiation project "Educational robotics for learning to program", seeking to encourage the learning of programming for students inside the campus.
- The work was carried out on the Instituto Federal do Espírito Santo Campus Colatina, and during the period in which I was a student in the Bachelor of Information Systems course.
- · For participation in robotics competitions/tournaments, the Asimov team was founded. Among the competitions, we participated in Brazilian and Latin American competitions.

Education



Udacity Brasil

Android Developer Nanodegree, Development of mobile applications 2018 - 2018

- · Created in partnership with Google, this course taught me to use various tools, principles, and standards that support the development of Android.
- During the course, 7 projects were sent using various tools and techniques, such as SQLite, Firebase Database, Firebase Storage, Firebase Cloud Message, Asynctask, Loaders, Picasso, Glide, Retrofit, Volley, Content Providers, Home Screen Widgets, Gradle, Material Design, Architecture Components...

👢 Ifes - Instituto Federal do Espírito Santo

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

2014 - 2018

- Graduation allowed me to acquire knowledge in several areas, from programming to administration disciplines. While in graduation I participated in two research projects and was a monitor of the course's programming.
- Regarding programming, I saw the following languages and tools during the course: C / C ++, Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, Java for Android, Java ServerPages, MySQL, MongoDB.
- · Course description according to the institution: The Bachelor of Information Systems course aims to train professionals to develop, implement and manage an information technology infrastructure, data, and systems that cover the entire organization.

Licenses & Certifications

Android Developer Nanodegree

The Complete Android Kotlin Developer Course - Udemy Brasil

- Aprenda Design Patterns com SOLID Udemy Brasil
- **Application security** Alura

Skills

Java • Kotlin • Scrum • Agile Methodologies • Algorithms • Mobile Application Development • Android Development • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

Honors & Awards

3rd PLACE in category IEEE Standard Educational Kit (SEK) at LARC/CBR (Competição Latino Americana e Brasileira de Robótica), IEEE SEK. - IEEE Nov 2015

4rd place in at TRUFES (Torneio de Robótica da UFES) - UFES Sep 2015